Samantha Pendleton BSc

IT GRADUATE | DATA SCIENTIST

ABERYSTWYTH, SY23 samanfapendle@outlook.com



github.com/sap218



twitter.com/sap218

PROFILE

Currently studying my Masters postgraduate degree in Data Science after completing my undergraduate degree in IT. I have an extensive set of skills, ranging from data science applications, bioinformatics, IT and communications. I am an organised individual, who works well through fast-paced environments and with colleagues. I have strong experience in assisting individuals, specifically students, throughout my employment and educational practises.

SKILLS

DATA SCIENCE

Bioinformatics, Statistics, Machine Learning, Data Mining

BUSINESS & COMMUNICATION

System Analyst, Business Planning, Visualisations and Presentations

LANGUAGES

Python & R; HTML, CSS, & PHP; SQL: PostgreSQL, SQLite, & NoSQL

IT

Administration, Operating Systems Cyber Security, Various Software

PROJECTS

» Postgraduate Masters Dissertation 2018

"Metagenomics of Acid Soil - a study of long reads" - Bioinformatics (computational biology) **acidoseq**: Python (v3.5) package on Acidobacteria; available: https://github.com/sap218/acidoseq

» Bioinformatics Research 2017

"An Analysis of current software for nanopore metagenomic data"

Computer Science department at Aberystwyth University; available: https://doi.org/10.1101/288969

EDUCATION

» **MSc (Masters)** candidate in Computer Science 2017-2018 – expected graduation 2019

Data Science at Aberystwyth University

Dissertation: "Metagenomics of Acid Soil - a study of long reads": Python (v3.5) package

In fulfilment of Masters Degree; Computer Science, Aberystwyth University

Additional: Advisor/Demonstrator, President of Computer Science Society

» BSc (Bachelors) graduate in Computer Science 2014-2017

2:1 Business Information Technology at Aberystwyth University

Dissertation: Web Major Project: The Little Cake Box; available: http://users.aber.ac.uk/sap21/

In fulfilment of the Bachelors Degree; Computer Science, Aberystwyth University

Additional: Demonstrator, Peer Mentor

» A-levels 2012-2014

IT (D*D*) Home Economics [Health & Social Care] (M)

Advanced Subsidiary: Mathematics & German Extra-Curricular: Art

EXPERIENCE

» Researcher, Bioinformatics; Aberystwyth University 2017

Project: "An analysis of current state of the art software on nanopore metagenomic data"

Poster: https://github.com/sap218/misc

» Assistant; Information Services at Hugh Owen Library, Aberystwyth University 2016-2017

Jobs: Assisted staff, attended focus groups, made strategy & floor plans

» Student Worker; AberWorks, Aberystwyth University 2016-2018

Jobs: Demonstrator/Advisor, Summer Operative: Ambassador

Classroom Assistant; Rimrose Hope Primary School 2011

Jobs: Helped plus guided pupils

» Volunteering/Charity Work; educational environments 2006-2017

Jobs: Environmental work, assisted with charity events, aiding the elderly

Peer mentor for the Computer Science Department

ACHIEVEMENTS

» BCS Lovelace Colloquium attendee 2017 – 2018

- Finalist ('18): An analysis of current software for nanopore metagenomic data

- Attendee ('17): Making sites attractive

Aberystwyth/Sheffield University Women's Conference; posters: https://github.com/sap218/misc

» Manual Handling Course 2016, 2017

Certificate from Aberystwyth University

» Diversity Certificate 2016+

Diversity in the workplace training from Aberystwyth University

» Work Shadowing Volunteer 2016

Peer Mentor participation at Aberystwyth University; Careers Service Volunteer Work Placement

INTERESTS

I enjoy a wide variety of activities; I appreciate cinematography, reading small fictional novels, and music. I am keen on puzzles; involving video games plus chess. Most of my time is spent on personal projects: I am keen on developing my knowledge in my spare time through web browsing. Projects can be found in my GitHub portfolio; with blogs regarding some of these projects can be found in my personal site here: https://sap218.github.io/.

PUBLICATIONS

"An analysis of current state of the art software on nanopore metagenomic data"

Samantha C Pendleton bioRxiv 288969; doi: https://doi.org/10.1101/288969

Note: article is a preprint and has not been peer-reviewed